osisoft.com 2019-02-06

# Privacy Policy

**Updated as of January 22, 2019**

This Privacy Policy explains how OSIsoft, LLC and its affiliates (“OSIsoft,” “we,” “our,” and “us”) may collect, use, secure and disclose information that personally identifies you (“Personal Information”). It also describes your choices regarding use, access and correction of your Personal Information. Such Personal Information may include, but is not limited to, your name, phone number, street address, and email address. 

OSIsoft is committed to respecting your privacy rights when you provide such information or visit any of the OSIsoft web sites (collectively, the “Site”), such as this one. To protect your Personal Information, OSIsoft has created the guidelines outlined below. Understanding that Internet technologies are rapidly evolving, any changes to this policy will be promptly posted on this page, with an updated “effective date” posted at the end of this policy. By accessing our Site or otherwise providing your Personal Information to us, you agree to and consent to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. 

### Information Collected

You may provide Personal Information to OSIsoft in a variety of ways. While visiting the Site, we may ask you to register and/or provide Personal Information for purposes of interacting with the Site. As other examples, OSIsoft may receive Personal Information when you: 

  * Provide or update licensing or account information 
  * Register for or attend OSIsoft-hosted or sponsored promotions and events (such as conferences, tradeshows or webinars) 
  * Order or use OSIsoft products, services or other offerings 
  * Communicate with OSIsoft for service or maintenance of OSIsoft products or services
  * Submit an application for employment with OSIsoft

When collecting Personal Information, we will specifically describe what information is required in order to provide you with the product or service, enter you in the promotion you have requested, respond to your inquiry or comment, or otherwise communicate with you. In order to access certain OSIsoft services, you may be required to sign in with OSIsoft Single Sign-On (SSO) credentials or another authentication mechanism. By signing into one OSIsoft service, you may be automatically signed into other OSIsoft services that use these credentials. 

This Privacy Policy only addresses the use and dissemination of information that we collect from you through processes like web forms, registrations, orders and technologies like cookies, as described below. To the extent that you disclose any information to other parties, whether through, for example, blogs, bulletin boards, and the like, through third party services or promotions offered on or through the Site or through other web sites throughout the Internet, different policies may apply and OSIsoft shall not be responsible for the use or dissemination of such information. 

### Cookies and Tracking Technologies

OSIsoft and its partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, gather demographic information about our user base as a whole, and to personalize your experience when you are visiting the Site. By tracking usage, we can best determine what features of the Site best serve the users. 

**What are cookies?** A cookie is a small data text file that a web site sends to your browser, which is then stored on your computer. The cookie is unique to the computer you are using and can only be read by the web site that placed the cookie on your computer. We cannot access cookies sent by other web sites or the information contained therein. Additionally, we cannot learn your email address or any other information about you using a cookie. The only way we would learn such information is if you specifically and voluntarily submit that information to us, for example, through a registration system, or by entering a sweepstakes or promotion. 

We could use an advertising server developed by a third party to display ads on the Site. Some of these ads may contain cookies that are sent by third parties (e.g., advertising agencies or advertising clients). We do not have access to these cookies or any information that they contain. We encourage you to contact the advertiser or its privacy policy for more information on these cookies. Links from other web sites that appear on the Site may also send cookies; but we do not control such activities. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising, click [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.

**What benefits do I receive from cookies?** Overall, the use of cookies helps to give you a more personalized experience at the Site. The information is used to keep our Site fresh and relevant to you, the user. Cookies can also identify you to our server, allowing you to avoid retyping your email address and password each time you access the Site.

**May I decline to accept a cookie?** You may decline to accept persistent cookies sent by the Site by selecting an option on your browser to reject cookies. You may wish to visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/), which contains comprehensive information on how to do this on a wide variety of browsers. You should always allow session cookies. If you do not allow session cookies, many areas of the Site will not be accessible to you. Session cookies enable us to send your request to the appropriate server, and allow that server to present your personalized content. 

**What analytics information do we collect?** As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer the site. 

### Use of Personal Information

We believe in protecting your privacy, and will not share your Personal Information with third parties outside of OSIsoft, except as described in this Privacy Policy. We believe we can enhance your experience on our Site and with our products and services with the information you share with us. 

We use Personal Information about you for a variety of purposes, such as to:

  * Fulfill your orders or respond to requests you make (e.g., for marketing materials from our Site) 
  * Manage your account with us, including account changes, billing and payments, customer support services, or software updates 
  * Improve our products, services and marketing efforts 
  * Issue OSIsoft accounts for access to our developers club 
  * Send administrative information, like product announcements or changes to contract terms or policies 
  * Personalize the Site’s content, layout and services 
  * Statistically analyze Site usage 
  * Present products and services to you that are tailored to your interests 
  * Send marketing communications, like educational materials or information about special offers or upcoming online or offline events, such as our Users Conferences 
  * Invite you to participate in various promotional activities, webcasts, campaigns, surveys and product tests, and to assess their effectiveness 
  * Diagnose and fix technical issues 
  * Monitor the security of our environments 
  * Respond to an inquiry from you regarding the information that we have collected
  * Assess and verify any job application that you submit to us
  * Respond to your comments and suggestions 

As part of your experience on our Site, you may receive communications from us related to products and services that might interest you. While we believe these services will enhance your experience at our Site, you will at all times be able to opt out from receiving these communications, either by specifically opting out of these services or by deleting your profile from our database. Please refer to “Opting-Out” for further reference. 

We have today, and will in the future have, arrangements with third party service providers, such as credit card processors, shipping companies and fulfillment services. When you sign up for a service we offer on the Site, we may be required to share Personal Information with that service provider in order to provide the service. These third party providers are required to comply with this policy and protect your information in the same way we do. They are not permitted to retain or use Personal Information for any purpose unrelated to providing the service. 

We may share your information with third-party business partners for such purposes as enhancing our products and services, or so that they can market their products or services to you. If you do not want us to share your Personal Information with these companies, please contact us at [privacy@osisoft.com](mailto:privacy@osisoft.com). 

We may receive information about you from other sources, including publicly available databases or third parties from whom we have purchased data, and combine this data with information we already have about you. This helps us to update, expand and analyze our records, identify new customers, and provide products and services that may be of interest to you. If you provide us Personal Information about others, or if others give us your information, we will only use that information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us. Examples of the types of information that may be obtained from public sources or purchased from third parties may include company name or industry. 

We may also disclose aggregated user statistics in order to describe our services to potential advertisers, partners, other third parties, our affiliate companies, and for other lawful purposes. We reserve the right to disclose Personal Information when needed to comply with the law or a legal process; respond to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements; cooperate with investigations of purported unlawful activities; identify persons violating the law; or in connection with the sale of part or all of OSIsoft’s or its affiliates’ stock or assets. 

### Party Collecting the Information

The Site may offer forums, blogs, message boards, or chat rooms as one of the services on the Site. If you disclose Personal Information in one of these forums, this information can be viewed, collected, and used by others. OSIsoft is not responsible for the use of information you disclose in these forums. We encourage you to consult the Forum Rules regarding the policies and procedures that apply to that portion of the Site. 

Our Site may operate as part of a larger group of sites, and may carry pages co-branded with our third-party business partners on which you may voluntarily choose to provide Personal Information directly to our partners. OSIsoft PI Developers Club and other services may also enable you to purchase, subscribe to, or use services, software, and content from companies other than OSIsoft (“Third-Party Offerings”). If you choose to purchase, subscribe to, or use a Third-Party Offering, we may provide the third party with your contact information and other Personal Information to enable the third party to provide its offering to you (and with your consent, send you promotional communications). In addition, other sites may use the Site’s or OSIsoft’s name. 

Since OSIsoft does not control the privacy policies of third parties, you are subject to the privacy customs and policies, if any, of such third parties, and OSIsoft shall not be responsible for the use or dissemination of your Personal Information by such parties. Therefore, we encourage you to ask questions and review those parties’ privacy policies before you disclose your Personal Information to others. If you wish to withdraw a prior consent allowing us to provide your Personal Information to a third party, please contact us at [privacy@osisoft.com](mailto:privacy@osisoft.com). 

### Links to Other Materials

Third party sites linked to and from the Site are not necessarily under the control of OSIsoft. OSIsoft shall have no responsibilities or liabilities whatsoever for the content or privacy practices of any such linked site or any link or linking program at any time. OSIsoft does not necessarily endorse companies (or related products or services) to or from which the Site is linked. If you decide to access any of the third party sites linked to the Site, you do so entirely at your own risk. 

### Children’s Privacy

OSIsoft cares about the safety of children and their use of the Internet. Therefore, in accordance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998, 5 U.S.C. §§ 6501-6505, we will never knowingly request or solicit personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without verifiable parental consent. In the event that we receive actual knowledge that we have collected such Personal Information without the requisite and verifiable parental consent, we will delete that information from our database as quickly as is practicable. 

###  International Transfer of Data

Your Personal Information may be stored and processed in any country where we have offices or in which we engage service providers. By accessing our Site or otherwise providing your Personal Information to us, you consent to the transfer and processing of such information to countries outside of your country of residence, including to the United States, which may have different data protection rules than in your country. Where your Personal Information is transmitted in this way, we take reasonable precautions to ensure that it remains secure and under our control. 

OSIsoft complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. OSIsoft has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov/](https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__www.privacyshield.gov_&d=DwMFAg&c=rxxrGm2iek7pTJSSe1mAiw&r=-w94_OPnehQAZrIDSL1JHyOxY7kw0N1Niv0qy2Lr1M4&m=z3zK3ySxNNg9N8TuXgbg7ZIBaQ-PifoKGIwhEFps5ck&s=8_PRlQgJycB-GK_GN0KtT6YFhGjg_KshYi6hf1squAw&e=). 

In the context of an onward transfer, OSIsoft has responsibility for the processing of Personal Information it receives under the Privacy Shield program and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. OSIsoft shall remain liable under the Principles if its agent processes such Personal Information in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless OSIsoft proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. 

Further, OSIsoft commits to cooperate with EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) and comply with the advice given by such authorities with regard to human resources data transferred from the EU and Switzerland in the context of the employment relationship. 

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, OSIsoft commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your Personal Information. EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact OSIsoft using the information below in the section Contacting Us. OSIsoft has further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to TRUSTe, an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please visit <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request> for more information or to file a complaint. The services of TRUSTe are provided at no cost to you. 

The possibility exists, under certain conditions, for an individual to invoke binding arbitration as indicated by [Annex I](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction) of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. With respect to Personal Information received or transferred under the Privacy Shield program, OSIsoft is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission (FTC). 

###  Data Retention

OSIsoft will retain your Personal Information as necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy, or as required by applicable laws or regulations. We will also retain and use your Personal Information to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

### Opting-Out

We respect your privacy and ability to choose whether to share information with us and any third party. You may choose to “opt-out” of sharing Personal Information in several ways. When choosing to use certain features or services on the Site, you can choose whether to share optional Personal Information in connection with the feature or service. If you receive communications from us that you prefer not to receive, you may opt out from receiving these communications by modifying the contact options in your registration profile. You may “opt-out” altogether from providing Personal Information to us by not registering on the Site and thereby not providing Personal Information. 

You may also choose to unsubscribe from communications from us by clicking [here](https://pages.osisoft.com/Subscription-Center-Unsubscribe.html) or on the Opt-Out/Unsubscribe link contained within email communications. 

Certain portions of the Site and certain services provided on the Site, however, do require registration in order to access or use these areas and services. If you choose not to register or provide certain information, these areas will not be accessible to you.

### Access to Your Information, Correction and Deletion

Upon request, OSIsoft will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your Personal Information. You may request to review, correct, delete, or otherwise modify any of the Personal Information that you have previously provided to us by sending an email to [privacy@osisoft.com](mailto:privacy@osisoft.com) with “Data Privacy” contained in the subject line. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

### Security

OSIsoft maintains above industry standard safeguards to ensure the security, integrity, and privacy of the Personal Information that you provide to OSIsoft. However, the security of information transmitted through the Internet can never be guaranteed. OSIsoft is not responsible for any interception or interruption of any communications through the Internet or for changes to or losses of information. 

Access to and use of a password protected and/or secure area of any OSIsoft Site is restricted to authorized users only. Users are responsible for maintaining the security of any password, user ID, or other form of authentication involved in obtaining access to password protected or secure areas of any OSIsoft Sites. In order to protect you and your information, OSIsoft may suspend your use of a web site, without notice and pending an investigation, if any breach of security is suspected. If you have any questions about the security of your Personal Information, you can contact us at [privacy@osisoft.com](mailto:privacy@osisoft.com). 

### Contacting Us

If you have any questions or comments about our Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at [privacy@osisoft.com](mailto:privacy@osisoft.com), or by regular mail addressed to: 

OSIsoft, LLC  
Attn: Legal Department – Privacy  
1600 Alvarado Street  
San Leandro, CA 94577  
United States 

### Effective Date and Changes

This Privacy Policy is effective as of January 22, 2019. OSIsoft reserves the right to modify the terms of this policy, at any time and in our sole discretion, by posting a change notice to this page. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. Your continued use of the Site or provision of Personal Information following our posting of a change notice will constitute binding acceptance of those changes. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
